<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:28:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Helpdesk.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pamima]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle east]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the arab world]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Massa Amini&#8217;s family members could not go to France to receive the posthumous human rights award. The family&#8217;s lawyer told AFP on Saturday that they were not allowed to board the scheduled flight. Massa Amini died on 16 September 2022 while in the custody of Iran&#8217;s Niti Police. She was arrested by the police for ... <a title="Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer" class="read-more" href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/" aria-label="More on Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Massa Amini&#8217;s family members could not go to France to receive the posthumous human rights award. The family&#8217;s lawyer told AFP on Saturday that they were not allowed to board the scheduled flight.</p>



<p>Massa Amini died on 16 September 2022 while in the custody of Iran&#8217;s Niti Police. She was arrested by the police for allegedly violating the strict dress code for women in Iran. Masa was 22 years old at the time of death.</p>



<p>Massa Amini&#8217;s family and supporters say he was killed in police custody. However, according to Iranian authorities, Masa died of an old, unknown illness.</p>



<p>Masa Amini was awarded the Shakharov Award posthumously in October this year. It is the EU&#8217;s highest human rights award. The global movement started around Massa&#8217;s death was also jointly awarded the award.</p>



<p>AFP spoke to Masa Amini&#8217;s family lawyer Shirin Ardakani in France yesterday. Amini&#8217;s parents and brother were not allowed to board the plane that was supposed to take them to France to attend the Shakharov Prize ceremony, he told AFP.</p>



<p>Ardakani said the family was barred from leaving Iran despite having valid visas. Passports have been confiscated.</p>



<p>The lawyer added, &#8220;Never before have the Iranian authorities been so proactive in preventing victims&#8217; families from speaking to the international community.&#8221;</p>



<p>Massive protests started in Iran over the death of Masa Amini. This led to a global movement called &#8216;Women, Life, Freedom&#8217;. The movement called for Iran to lift the hijab requirement for women and for the country to end its &#8220;Muslim cleric-led&#8221; government.</p>



<p>Iranian security forces have repressed these protests. Hundreds of people were killed. Several people have also been executed in Iran. They were sentenced to death for their involvement in the protests. The Iranian authorities called the protest a &#8216;riot&#8217;.</p>



<p>Shakharov&#8217;s prize is due to be presented at a ceremony at the European Parliament on December 13. The prize money is 50 thousand euros.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pamima]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vote]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Voting for the presidential election has started in Egypt today from Sunday. Voting will continue for three days from 9 am to 9 pm local time. The election is believed to see incumbent President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi in power for a third term. Election results are scheduled to be announced on December 18. Critics say ... <a title="Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election" class="read-more" href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/" aria-label="More on Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Voting for the presidential election has started in Egypt today from Sunday. Voting will continue for three days from 9 am to 9 pm local time. The election is believed to see incumbent President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi in power for a third term.</p>



<p>Election results are scheduled to be announced on December 18.</p>



<p>Critics say the election is rigged after decades of crackdowns on dissidents in Egypt. However, government media say that this election is a step towards political pluralism.</p>



<p>Egypt is in economic crisis. The country is facing a shortage of foreign exchange, and the country is on the brink of record inflation. If Sisi returns to power for another six-year term, he will have to prioritize solving these problems. Meanwhile, the war between Israel and Hamas is going on in the bordering Gaza Strip. Sisi must also ensure that the effects of this war do not spread to Egypt.</p>



<p>The three candidates who are fighting against Sisi in the election are not very well known. The most likely candidate to challenge Sisi also announced his withdrawal from the race in October. He alleged that miscreants and officials attacked his supporters. However, Egypt&#8217;s National Electoral Authority denied the allegation.</p>



<p>Local media in Egypt are tightly controlled by the Egyptian authorities. They are using local media to call people to vote. However, some of the people of Egypt say that they did not know when the election will be held even a few days before the election. Others say that there will be no change in the vote.</p>



<p>Aya Mohamed, a 35-year-old marketing executive, said, &#8216;I know there is an election. But it is not known when it is happening. I know this much because I have seen big campaigns for Sisi on the streets. I have no idea about the election. Because, it will not really change anything.&#8217;</p>



<p>Sisi led the 2013 coup against Egypt&#8217;s first democratically elected president, Mohamed Morsi. The following year, Sisi was elected president with 97 percent of the vote. Since then, the Sisi-led government has continued to crack down on liberal and left-wing activists. Thousands of people were imprisoned. Sisi was re-elected in 2018 with 97 percent of the vote.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UN Security Council is dysfunctional: Guterres</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/un-security-council-is-dysfunctional-guterres/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/un-security-council-is-dysfunctional-guterres/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pamima]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloody Palestine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palestine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has expressed regret over the failure of a UN Security Council resolution calling for a cease-fire in the Gaza Strip. He condemned the division among the council members for this failure. Guterres said the lack of consensus among members has made the Security Council ineffective. The United Nations Secretary General made ... <a title="UN Security Council is dysfunctional: Guterres" class="read-more" href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/un-security-council-is-dysfunctional-guterres/" aria-label="More on UN Security Council is dysfunctional: Guterres">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has expressed regret over the failure of a UN Security Council resolution calling for a cease-fire in the Gaza Strip. He condemned the division among the council members for this failure. Guterres said the lack of consensus among members has made the Security Council ineffective.</p>



<p>The United Nations Secretary General made this comment on Sunday after participating in the Doha Forum in Qatar. A day before last Friday, the ceasefire proposal was raised in the Security Council. 13 out of 15 members of the council supported the proposal. However, it ultimately failed due to the veto of the permanent member United States.</p>



<p>In a speech in Doha, Antonio Guterres said the Security Council was &#8220;paralyzed by the geographical fragmentation&#8221; of its members. Due to this division, the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas, a Palestinian independence organization, cannot be resolved. The &#8216;credibility&#8217; of the United Nations is suffering greatly.</p>



<p>Guterres said the situation in Gaza was deteriorating so rapidly that it was heading towards a &#8220;catastrophe&#8221;, pledging to continue efforts towards a ceasefire in Gaza. The effect would be that the Palestinians might not be able to turn around. The Gaza conflict will also affect peace and security in the region.</p>



<p>Earlier, a cease-fire was implemented in Gaza from November 24 to 30. This was made possible through the mediation of several parties, including Qatar. Qatari Prime Minister Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdul Rahman Al Thani spoke about continuing to try for a new ceasefire at the Doha Forum. But he complained that Qatar is showing as much interest in a ceasefire as Hamas or Israel.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A strong attack in the south</h2>



<p>Israel thanked the United States for taking a stand against the ceasefire in the Security Council. The country&#8217;s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said last Saturday that they will continue fighting to eliminate Hamas. In a similar gesture, the country&#8217;s army chief, Herzi Halevi, said his forces would use more force in Gaza.</p>



<p>After the statement of the Israeli Prime Minister and the Chief of the Army, the Israeli forces intensified their attack on South Gaza on Sunday. Hamas said Israeli forces had carried out an &#8220;extremely violent operation&#8221; in the Khan Younis area in the south. Injured people were seen in Nasser Hospital there. The road from Khan Younis to the Rafah area on the Egyptian border was also attacked.</p>



<p>Residents of central Gaza also reported clashes. Israeli tanks shelled Buraiz and Maghazi refugee camps in this area. Palestinian health officials said seven people were killed in an Israeli airstrike in Buraiz camp.</p>



<p>According to the Ministry of Health of Gaza, since the beginning of the conflict on October 7, more than 17 thousand 700 people have been killed in the valley by Israel&#8217;s attacks. 40 percent of them are under 18 years of age. Meanwhile, Israel&#8217;s National Security Adviser Zaki Hanegbi said they killed at least 7,000 Hamas fighters in Gaza. However, he did not mention how this number was determined.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">&#8216;Half of Gaza&#8217;s people are starving&#8217;</h2>



<p>Not only are there casualties in Gaza, but the number of hungry people is increasing day by day. Last Friday, UN World Food Program (WFP) Deputy Director Carl Schau visited Gaza. Later he said that half of the people of Gaza are starving. There is not enough food.</p>



<p>In a post on X (formerly Twitter), Carl Schau added that little of the much-needed relief aid is getting into Gaza. 9 out of 10 residents here do not have enough food every day. Pointing to continued Israeli attacks, he said the situation in Gaza had made it &#8220;almost impossible&#8221; for aid to arrive.</p>



<p>The Rafah crossing on the Gaza-Egypt border is now open. Aid is limited to Gaza through this crossing. Israeli military spokesman Lt. Col. Richard Hecht told the BBC on Saturday that every effort is being made to get as much aid as possible to Gaza.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/un-security-council-is-dysfunctional-guterres/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
