<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Egypt &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/tag/egypt/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:26:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Helpdesk.png</url>
	<title>Egypt &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pamima]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vote]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Voting for the presidential election has started in Egypt today from Sunday. Voting will continue for three days from 9 am to 9 pm local time. The election is believed to see incumbent President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi in power for a third term. Election results are scheduled to be announced on December 18. Critics say ... <a title="Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election" class="read-more" href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/" aria-label="More on Voting is underway in Egypt&#8217;s presidential election">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Voting for the presidential election has started in Egypt today from Sunday. Voting will continue for three days from 9 am to 9 pm local time. The election is believed to see incumbent President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi in power for a third term.</p>



<p>Election results are scheduled to be announced on December 18.</p>



<p>Critics say the election is rigged after decades of crackdowns on dissidents in Egypt. However, government media say that this election is a step towards political pluralism.</p>



<p>Egypt is in economic crisis. The country is facing a shortage of foreign exchange, and the country is on the brink of record inflation. If Sisi returns to power for another six-year term, he will have to prioritize solving these problems. Meanwhile, the war between Israel and Hamas is going on in the bordering Gaza Strip. Sisi must also ensure that the effects of this war do not spread to Egypt.</p>



<p>The three candidates who are fighting against Sisi in the election are not very well known. The most likely candidate to challenge Sisi also announced his withdrawal from the race in October. He alleged that miscreants and officials attacked his supporters. However, Egypt&#8217;s National Electoral Authority denied the allegation.</p>



<p>Local media in Egypt are tightly controlled by the Egyptian authorities. They are using local media to call people to vote. However, some of the people of Egypt say that they did not know when the election will be held even a few days before the election. Others say that there will be no change in the vote.</p>



<p>Aya Mohamed, a 35-year-old marketing executive, said, &#8216;I know there is an election. But it is not known when it is happening. I know this much because I have seen big campaigns for Sisi on the streets. I have no idea about the election. Because, it will not really change anything.&#8217;</p>



<p>Sisi led the 2013 coup against Egypt&#8217;s first democratically elected president, Mohamed Morsi. The following year, Sisi was elected president with 97 percent of the vote. Since then, the Sisi-led government has continued to crack down on liberal and left-wing activists. Thousands of people were imprisoned. Sisi was re-elected in 2018 with 97 percent of the vote.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/voting-is-underway-in-egypts-presidential-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
