<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>France &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/tag/france/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:28:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Helpdesk.png</url>
	<title>France &#8211; Helpdesk Physics</title>
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pamima]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle east]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the arab world]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Massa Amini&#8217;s family members could not go to France to receive the posthumous human rights award. The family&#8217;s lawyer told AFP on Saturday that they were not allowed to board the scheduled flight. Massa Amini died on 16 September 2022 while in the custody of Iran&#8217;s Niti Police. She was arrested by the police for ... <a title="Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer" class="read-more" href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/" aria-label="More on Iran did not allow Massa Amini&#8217;s family to go to France to receive the Shakharov Prize: lawyer">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Massa Amini&#8217;s family members could not go to France to receive the posthumous human rights award. The family&#8217;s lawyer told AFP on Saturday that they were not allowed to board the scheduled flight.</p>



<p>Massa Amini died on 16 September 2022 while in the custody of Iran&#8217;s Niti Police. She was arrested by the police for allegedly violating the strict dress code for women in Iran. Masa was 22 years old at the time of death.</p>



<p>Massa Amini&#8217;s family and supporters say he was killed in police custody. However, according to Iranian authorities, Masa died of an old, unknown illness.</p>



<p>Masa Amini was awarded the Shakharov Award posthumously in October this year. It is the EU&#8217;s highest human rights award. The global movement started around Massa&#8217;s death was also jointly awarded the award.</p>



<p>AFP spoke to Masa Amini&#8217;s family lawyer Shirin Ardakani in France yesterday. Amini&#8217;s parents and brother were not allowed to board the plane that was supposed to take them to France to attend the Shakharov Prize ceremony, he told AFP.</p>



<p>Ardakani said the family was barred from leaving Iran despite having valid visas. Passports have been confiscated.</p>



<p>The lawyer added, &#8220;Never before have the Iranian authorities been so proactive in preventing victims&#8217; families from speaking to the international community.&#8221;</p>



<p>Massive protests started in Iran over the death of Masa Amini. This led to a global movement called &#8216;Women, Life, Freedom&#8217;. The movement called for Iran to lift the hijab requirement for women and for the country to end its &#8220;Muslim cleric-led&#8221; government.</p>



<p>Iranian security forces have repressed these protests. Hundreds of people were killed. Several people have also been executed in Iran. They were sentenced to death for their involvement in the protests. The Iranian authorities called the protest a &#8216;riot&#8217;.</p>



<p>Shakharov&#8217;s prize is due to be presented at a ceremony at the European Parliament on December 13. The prize money is 50 thousand euros.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/iran-did-not-allow-massa-aminis-family-to-go-to-france-to-receive-the-shakharov-prize-lawyer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
