<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>fashion &#8211; Helpdesk Physics Ucla</title>
	<atom:link href="https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/tag/fashion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:52:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Teens to forty-somethings are now wearing the same clothes</title>
		<link>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/teens-to-forty-somethings-are-now-wearing-the-same-clothes/</link>
					<comments>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/teens-to-forty-somethings-are-now-wearing-the-same-clothes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xamzla]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dress up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/?p=948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Everyone wants comfortable clothes in summer. Kurta or top can be worn almost everywhere now. Choose cut, materials and work according to the environment. From [&#8230;]</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="storyCard eyOoS">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><span>Everyone wants comfortable clothes in summer. Kurta or top can be worn almost everywhere now. Choose cut, materials and work according to the environment. From teenagers to forty-somethings are now comfortable in this dress. Fashion houses also vary in offering all kinds of cuts, from indigenous to western. The same kurta can be worn with pants of different cuts to break the monotony. Kurtas are still loosely cut. Buyers are showing interest in soft fabrics and less work. This is useful in this climate. Loose long or short kurtas, tops or shirts are also trending. Both style and comfort are available on busy days.</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="print-adslot adsBox _4Pk8L _0Zwdj">
<div class="dfp-ad-unit Tlph-" data-lang="বিজ্ঞাপন">
<div class="adunitContainer">
<div id="News_InArticle_300x250-9e3d4d73-634f-4c9f-aed0-a50fc91f66a3-0-0" class=" adBox" data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"><span>This type of tunic is very ideal during any festival. </span><span>Made of viscose satin, the top is comfortable to wear even in hot weather. </span><span>A festive atmosphere has also come due to the colors. </span><span>The golden chumki work done near the neck has given a gorgeous look. </span><span>Chumki has red, beige and white thread work. </span><span>Apart from block print all over the top there is machine and hand work. </span><span>Bishop cut is predominant in sleeve cut. </span><span>Being loose will also make you feel comfortable.</span>As the color and design of the top is light, it can be worn during the day. Again, work and color &#8211; both are elite, so it will suit any evening or evening party.</div>
<div data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"></div>
<div data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"><span>It is perfect for those who find comfort in long cut kurtas. </span><span>Block print and machine embroidery work dominates the entire outfit. </span><span>Top to bottom cutwork work has been added to the button front portion of the dress. </span><span>Cutwork work on the collar as well. </span><span>Smoking work at the end of the sleeve. </span><span>There is a separate belt for the waist.</span></div>
<div data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"><span>Made of silk fabric, this top is designed using sublimation print (a type of digital print). </span><span>Waist smoking design brings a different dimension.</span></div>
</div>
<div data-google-query-id="CLyc4MW984EDFfxQnQkd0UgGfQ"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://helpdesk.physics.ucla.edu/teens-to-forty-somethings-are-now-wearing-the-same-clothes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
